


//Question ba
var questionBank = [{


        main: 'Listening',
        desc: 'Julia is telling Dan about her new house. Listen and circle the correct words.',
        question: 'There are two .....',
        option: ['bedrooms', 'bathrooms', 'closets'],
        answer: 'bathrooms'
    },
    {
        main: 'Listening',
        desc: 'Julia is telling Dan about her new house. Listen and circle the correct words.',
        question: 'There are some chairs in the....',
        option: ['dining room', 'kitchen', 'living room'],
        answer: 'living room'
    },
    {
        main: 'Listening',
        desc: 'Julia is telling Dan about her new house. Listen and circle the correct words.',
        question: 'Julia needs a.......for the kitchen.',
        option: ['microwave oven', 'refrigerator', 'stove'],
        answer: 'microwave oven'
    },

    {
        main: 'Grammar',      
        desc: 'Complete the conversation. Choose the correct form of be.',
        question: 'a. Jack:Excuse me. _________________ you Isabel? ',
        option: ['Are', 'Is', 'Am'],
        answer: 'Are'
    },
                        {
        main: 'Grammar',      
        desc: 'Complete the conversation. Choose the correct form of be.',
        question: 'b. Isabel:Yes, I _________________ .',
        option: ['am', 'is', 'am not'],
        answer: 'am'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',      
        desc: 'Complete the conversation. Choose the correct form of be.',
        question: 'c. Jack:_________________ your family from Mexico?',
        option: ['Is', 'Are', 'Am'],
        answer: 'Is'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Complete the conversation. Choose the correct form of be.',
        question: 'd. Isabel:No. We _________________ from Brazil.',
        option: ['are', 'is', 'am'],
        answer: 'are'

    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Complete the conversation. Choose the correct form of be.',
        question: 'e. Jack:What _________________ your first language, Isabel?',
        option: ['is', 'are', 'am'],
        answer: 'is'

    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Complete the conversation. Choose the correct form of be.',
        question: 'f. Isabel: It _________________ Portuguese.',
        option: ['am', 'are', 'is'],
        answer: 'is'

    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct possessives.',
        question: '....I....',
        option: ['My', 'His', 'Her'],
        answer: 'My'

    },
                       {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct possessives.',
        question: '....You....',
        option: ['You', 'Your', 'His'],
        answer: 'Your'

    },
                          {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct possessives.',
        question: '....He....',
        option: ['My', 'His', 'Her'],
        answer: 'His'

    },
                    
                          {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct possessives.',
        question: '....She....',
        option: ['My', 'His', 'Her'],
        answer: 'Her'

    },
                           {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct possessives.',
        question: '....We....',
        option: ['Our', 'We', 'Us'],
        answer: 'Our'

    },
                              {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the sentences.',
        question: 'Robert is handsome. He\’s very _________ .',
        option: ['friendly', 'good-looking', 'serious'],
        answer: 'good-looking'

    },    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the sentences.',
        question: 'Anne works in a store, and she handles money. She\’s a _________ .',
        option: ['cashier', 'pilot', 'musician'],
        answer: 'cashier'

    },
                       {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the sentences.',
        question: 'Mia doesn\’t like her job. It\’s very _________ .',
        option: ['interesting', 'exciting', 'boring'],
        answer: 'boring'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the sentences.',
        question: 'Mario is Celia\’s father. Celia is Mario\’s _________ .',
        option: ['wife', 'daughter', 'sister'],
        answer: 'daughter'
    },
                      {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the sentences.',
        question: 'It\’s 10:00 A.M., and Zachary is sleeping. He gets up late _________ Saturdays.',
        option: ['at', 'on', 'in'],
        answer: 'on'
    },
                        {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words.',
        question: 'It\’s cold today, _______________ it\’s very windy.',
        option: ['and', 'but', 'so'],
        answer: 'and'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words.',
        question: 'It\’s noon, ________ we\’re eating lunch.',
        option: ['and', 'but', 'so'],
        answer: 'so'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words.',
        question: 'John is wearing shoes, ________ he isn\’t wearing socks.',
        option: ['and', 'but', 'so'],
        answer: 'but'
    },
                      {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words.',
        question: 'Jay is reading a nice story, ______________________ he is not listening to music.',
        option: ['and', 'but', 'so'],
        answer: 'but'
    },
                    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct responses',
        question: 'A: Have a good evening. B: __________',
        option: [
            'It\’s nice to meet you.',
            'Not bad, thanks.',
            'Thanks. Good night, Ashley.'
        ],
        answer: 'Thanks. Good night, Ashley.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct responses',
        question: 'A: What\’s Marta like? B: __________',
        option: [
            'She\’s from Mexico.',
            'She\’s very nice.',
            'She\’s eighteen.'
        ],
        answer: 'She\’s very nice.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct responses',
        question: 'A: I need a pen. B: __________',
        option: [
            'Let me see. Yes, it is.',
            'No problem. Thank you.',
            'There\’s a pen on the desk.'
        ],
        answer: 'There’s a pen on the desk.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct responses',
        question: 'A: When do you study?        B: __________ ',
        option: [
            'Yes, a lot.',
            'At school.',
            'In the evening.'
        ],
        answer: 'In the evening.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct responses',
        question: 'A: Where are my keys? B: __________ ',
        option: [
            'They\’re under your hat.',
            'It\’s on your briefcase.',
            'There are three.'
        ],
        answer: 'They\’re under your hat.'
    },
                    
]

var question = document.getElementById('question');
var quizContainer = document.getElementById('quiz-container');
var scorecard = document.getElementById('scorecard');
var main = document.getElementById('main');
var desc = document.getElementById('desc');

var option0 = document.getElementById('option0');
var option1 = document.getElementById('option1');
var option2 = document.getElementById('option2');
var option3 = document.getElementById('option3');
var next = document.querySelector('.next');
var previous = document.querySelector('.previous');
var points = document.getElementById('score');
var span = document.querySelectorAll('span');
var stat = document.querySelector('#stat');
var AudioA = document.getElementById('listeningA');
var i = 0;
var score = 0;

//function to display questions
function displayQuestion() {

    for (var a = 0; a < span.length; a++) {
        span[a].style.background = 'none';
    }

    main.innerHTML = '' + questionBank[i].main;
    desc.innerHTML = '' + questionBank[i].desc;
    question.innerHTML = 'Q.' + (i + 1) + ' ' + questionBank[i].question;
    if (i === 5) {
        AudioA.style.display = "none";

    }
    option0.innerHTML = questionBank[i].option[0];
    option1.innerHTML = questionBank[i].option[1];
    option2.innerHTML = questionBank[i].option[2];
    stat.innerHTML = "Question" + ' ' + (i + 1) + ' ' + 'of' + ' ' + questionBank.length;

}

//function to calculate scores
function calcScore(e) {
    if (e.innerHTML === questionBank[i].answer && score < questionBank.length) {
        score = score + 1;

    }
    setTimeout(nextQuestion, 300);
}
//function to display next question
function nextQuestion() {

    if (i < questionBank.length - 1) {
        i = i + 1;
        displayQuestion();

    } else {
        points.innerHTML = score;
        quizContainer.style.display = 'none';
        scoreboard.style.display = 'block'
    }


}

//function to display previous question
function previousQuestion() {
    if (i <= questionBank.length - 1) {
        i = i - 1;
        if (i <= 5) {
            AudioA.style.display = "block";
        }
        displayQuestion();
    }
}
//click events to previous button
previous.addEventListener('click', previousQuestion);
//click events to next button
next.addEventListener('click', nextQuestion);






displayQuestion();

audio.onclick = function() {
    window.addEventListener("click", function() {

        document.querySelector(".iframe").style.display = "block";
        document.querySelector("#close").style.display = "block";


    });



}
var btn = document.getElementById("close");

btn.onclick = function() {

    window.addEventListener("click", function() {

        document.querySelector(".iframe").style.display = "none";

        document.querySelector("#close").style.display = "none";

    });
}

function send_handle() {

    let num = document.getElementById("number").value;
    let msg = document.getElementById("msg").value;
    let msg1 = document.getElementById("msg1");
    msg = points.innerHTML;
    let name = document.getElementById("name").value;
    if (name == "") {
        msg1.innerHTML = "لا يمكنك ترك الاسم فارغا";
        parent.location = "indexIntroA.html?#scorecard";
    } else {
        var win = open(`https://wa.me/${num}?text=أنا الطالب : ${name}%20كود الإختبار هو :9582${msg}_IAOTS`, 'self');
        // win.focus();
    }
}

window.onbeforeunload = function() {
    return "Dude, are you sure you want to leave? Think of the kittens!";
}

var sec = 3600,
    countDiv = document.getElementById("timer"),
    secpass,
    countDown = setInterval(function() {
        'use strict';

        secpass();
    }, 1000);

function secpass() {
    'use strict';

    var min = Math.floor(sec / 60),
        remSec = sec % 60;

    if (remSec < 10) {

        remSec = '0' + remSec;

    }
    if (min < 10) {

        min = '0' + min;

    }
    countDiv.innerHTML = min + ":" + remSec;

    if (sec > 0) {

        sec = sec - 1;

    } else {

        clearInterval(countDown);

        countDiv.innerHTML = 'countdown done';

    }
}
